Paulo Leonardo Benatto

Brighton, UK benatto@gmail.com Phone: +44 07533998484 Post Code: BN21HF

Summary

My name is Paulo Leonardo Benatto, aka Patito, a Brazillian software developer that resembles a hobbit _o/. I graduated in Computer Science in 2008, however, I have been working with Linux since 2002. I started with Debian Potato (mount /dev/fd0 =), good times!

After university I moved to Florianopolis, a city in south Brazil, where I started working as a Jr. Software Developer. Since then I have worked in several companies using different technologies, such as: C/C++, Python, JavaScript, Linux and so on.

In 2014, I decided to leave Brazil and try a new experience in England, make new friends and drink some pints. I started working as busser at Planet Hollywood. It was a fun job, but hard in the same time. After 2 months working in Planet Hollywood, Brandwatch invited me to hold a position as Linux System Administrator and I had a chance to learn a lot about the sysadmin/devops world.

At the end of last year I began learning the Go programming language, I bought some books, attended a Go conference and started following the Go community. This year I was given the opportunity to work at Sainsburys Digital Labs where I'm developing microservices in GoLang.

I believe I am a good mood person that enjoys working in agile teams and open-minded companies. I also consider myself hardworking with can-do attitude and I really like to learn and share knowledge.

Education

Universidade Estadual do Oeste do Parana, BSc in Computer Science, December 2007.

Experience

Brandwatch

Jul 2016 - Present

 $Core\ Systems\ Engineer$

Main Technologies: Go, Python, Linux, Git;

I'm part of a team that develops a project called Bigode that is a centralized configuration state aggregator that presents information on all the significant assets in your IT environment. It is part of my day developing REST API in Go, CLI tools in python and some contact with JavaScript to develop the frontend.

Sainsbury's

Feb 2016 - Jul 2016

Go Developer

Main Technologies: Go, Ansible, Git;

Developing micro-services using Go programming language. I'm using ansible and vagrant to deploy the services, RabbitMQ to communicate between the services and Docker for my test environment.

Brandwatch

Jul 2014 - Feb 2016

 $Linux\ Systems\ Administrator$

Main Technologies: Linux, Python, Bareos, Ansible, Git;

A mix between software development (Python, JavaScript, HTML) and Linux Administration (Debian, Ansible, Puppet, Bareos Backup, Nagios, Sensu, LDAP).

 \mathbf{DBA}

Dec 2013 - Feb 2014

Software Engineer

Main Technologies: Linux, Python, Raspberry PI and C;

Member of a team responsible to design and develop a system to analyse vehicle traffic on Brazilian highways. The product was develop using C, Python and Linux OS.

SEC+ Dec 2012 - Dec 2013

Software Engineer

Main Technologies: Linux, Python, Django Framework, JavaScript and C;

Back-end development of web system for intelligent monitoring and management of natural disasters using Python and the Django framework. Front-end with Javascript (JQuery, Bootstrap, Google Maps API),bJSON, HTML5, CSS. Modeling and use of object-relational database and geographic objects with PostgreSQL/PostGIS.

Digitro Technology - NDS

Jan 2012 - Dec 2012

Software Engineer

Main Technologies: Linux, C/C++, Java, ShellScript;

Member of the team responsible to design and develop the roadmap features of a product called Guardião used to intercept calls and internet trafic of people whose are being investigated by the police. Specifically allocated on the design and development of a module which main goal is to intercept the actions done on Facebook, WhatsApp and Hotmail of a target, using the gathered data to cross reference with another possible targets.

Main activities: C Development, Scripting, Linux administration, Network Packet Analysis (Wireshark), debugging and testing software.

Digitro Technology - STE

Set 2008 - Dec 2011

Software Engineer

Main Technologies: Linux, VoIP, C/C++, shellscript, protocols: UDP, TCP, SIP;

Member of a team responsible to design and develop VoIP products such as IP phone and softphone. Most of the projects were developed in C ANSI language under Linux and Windows operating system.

Other activities involves: Linux administration, Python and Shell scripting, Network Packet analysis, debugging, profiling, code analysis, /etc.

Skills Base

Operating System: Linux (Debian, Ubuntu, CentOS), Windows NT/XP/Vista/7 and OSX;

Networkings: TCP/IP protocol suite;

Progamming Languages: C/C++, Pascal, Python, Go, JavaScript, plus some experience with Lua and Java;

Languages: Fluent in Portuguese, Intermediate in English and Spanish;

Open Source Projects

- libpenetra: The libpenetra was created with the goal of studying the windows binary format known as Portable Executable (PE). With libpenetra you can access all information about PE binaries. (https://github.com/patito/libpenetra)
- **libmalelf**: The libmalelf is an evil library that SHOULD be used for good! It was developed with the intent to assist in the process of infecting binaries and provide a safe way to analyze malwares. (https://github.com/SecPlus/libmalelf)

More Info

- Linkedin: http://www.linkedin.com/in/benatto
- **Github**: https://github.com/patito